[OPTIONAL] forms-010 The input element: text

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state text is supported.

If a text input field is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-020 The input element: password

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state password is supported.

If text entered in the preceding box is not displayed visually, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-030 The input element: tel

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state tel is supported.

To verify, test a telephone number that matches the pattern 123-456-7890 and one that does not.

If the reading system reports an error only when a non-matching pattern is entered, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-040 The input element: url

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state url is supported.

To verify, test a valid and invalid URL.

If the reading system reports an error only on when an invalid URL is entered, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-050 The input element: email

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state email is supported.

To verify, test a valid and invalid email.

If the reading system reports an error only when an invalid email address is entered, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-060 The input element: date

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state date is supported.

If the preceding input field allows dates to be selected and input, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-070 The input element: number

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state number is supported.

If the preceding input field allows positive and negative numbers to be selected and input, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-080 The input element: range

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state range is supported.

If a slider control is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-090 The input element: checkbox

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state checkbox is supported.

Test

If a checkbox control is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-100 The input element: radio

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state radio is supported.

Test

If a radio button control is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-110 The input element: file

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state file is supported.

If a file selection control is not rendered immediately before this paragraph, and files can be selected from the local file system, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-120 The input element: submit

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state submit is supported.

If a submit input button is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-130 The input element: image

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state image is supported.

If a round play button is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-140 The input element: reset

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state reset is supported.

If a reset button is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-150 The input element: button

Tests whether the HTML5 input element state button is supported.

If a button with the label "Test" is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-210 The button element

Tests whether the HTML5 button element is supported.

Test

If a button with the label "Test" is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-220 The select element: single option

Tests whether the HTML5 select element is supported for picking a single option.

lorem ipsum dolor

If a drop-down selection box with the options "lorem", "ipsum" and "dolor" is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-230 The select element: multiple options

Tests whether the HTML5 select element is supported for picking multiple options.

lorem ipsum dolor

If a selection box allowing any or all of options "lorem", "ipsum" and "dolor" to be selected is rendered immediately before this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-240 The optgroup element

Tests whether the HTML5 optgroup element is supported for grouping options under a common heading.

lorem ipsum dolor

If the non-selectable heading "Latin" groups the options "lorem", "ipsum" and "dolor" in the preceding selection box, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-250 The datalist element

Tests whether the HTML5 datalist element for predefining options is supported.

lorem ipsum dolor

If, when activating the preceding text box, the options "lorem", "ipsum" and "dolor" are made available for selection, the test passes. If the three options are visible as text below the selection box, the test fails.

[OPTIONAL] forms-260 The textarea element

Tests whether the HTML5 textarea element is supported.

If a 40 column by 5 row text area precedes this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-270 The progress element

Tests whether the HTML5 progress element is supported.

If a progress bar precedes this paragraph, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] forms-280 The meter element

Tests whether the HTML5 meter element is supported.

If a meter bar precedes this paragraph, the test passes.

style-010The CSS List properties: markers for unordered list

Test whether the list-style-type property is supported on a ul element.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has circle markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has square markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has disc markers, the test passes.

style-020The CSS List properties: markers for ordered list

Test whether the list-style-type property is supported on a ol element.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has upper-roman markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has upper-alpha markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has upper-latin markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has lower-alpha markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has lower-greek markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has lower-latin markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has lower-roman markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has armenian markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has cjk-ideographic markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has decimal markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has decimal-leading-zero markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has georgian markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has hebrew markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has hiragana markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has hiragana-iroha markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has katakana markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has katakana-iroha markers, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has no marker, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has basic markers, the test passes.

style-030The CSS List properties: list-style property (shorthand)

Test whether the list-style shorthand property is supported using a gif on a ul element.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list has the purple and aqua square bullet the test passes.

style-040The CSS List properties: list-style-position

Test whether the list-style-position property is supported on a ul element.

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.

If the Lorem Ipsum list has markers inside the indentation, the test passes.

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.

If the Lorem Ipsum list has the default setting (marker outside the indentation), the test passes.

style-050The HTML start attribute for ordered lists

Test whether the start attribute is supported on a ol element.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list starts at 25, the test passes.

Lorem
Ipsum
Dolor
Sit
Amet

If the Lorem Ipsum list starts at 'L' (50), the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] pls-010 PLS: IPA Support

Tests whether PLS lexicons with IPA pronunciations are supported.

Today

If the preceding word is pronounced "tomorrow", IPA lexicons are supported.

[OPTIONAL] pls-020 PLS: X-SAMPA Support

Tests whether PLS lexicons with X-SAMPA pronunciations are supported.

Daily

If the preceding word is pronounced "weekly", X-SAMPA lexicons are supported.

[OPTIONAL] pls-030 PLS: Mixed Lexicon Support

Tests whether X-SAMPA and IPA pronunciations can be mixed in a single lexicon file.

Despair

If the preceding word is pronounced "joy", mixed lexicons are supported.

[OPTIONAL] pls-040 PLS: Multilingual Support

Tests whether PLS lexicons are supported for embedded languages.

Comparing apples to oranges.

If the preceding sentence is pronounced "comparing apples to apples" the test passes, otherwise it fails.

[OPTIONAL] pls-050 PLS: Case Sensitivity

Tests whether PLS lexicons entries are case sensitive.

Bass not bass.

If the preceding sentence is pronounced "comparing apples to apples" the test passes, otherwise it fails.

[OPTIONAL] ssml-010 SSML: IPA Support

Tests whether SSML support for IPA pronunciations is available.

Friday

If the word "Friday" is pronouned "Monday" the test passes, otherwise it fails.

[OPTIONAL] speech-020 SSML: X-SAMPA Support

Tests whether SSML support for X-SAMPA pronunciations is available.

Friday

If the word "Friday" is pronouned "Monday" the test passes, otherwise it fails.

[OPTIONAL] speech-010 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak none

Tests whether content styled using the none value is omitted from aural rendering.

This paragraph should not be announced.

If no text is announced after the description, the test passes. If the text "this paragraph should not be announced" is rendered, the test fails.

[OPTIONAL] speech-020 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak normal

Tests whether hidden content is announced when the -epub-speak property is set to normal.

I am a hidden paragraph.

If no text is announced after the description, the test falis. I the text "I am a hidden paragraph" is rendered, the test fails.

[OPTIONAL] speech-030 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak-as spell

Tests support for speaking out letters in a word or acronym one at a time.

water

The test fails if the the word "water" is not spelled out one character at a time.

[OPTIONAL] speech-040 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak-as digits

Tests support for speaking out digits in a number one at a time.

42

If the numbers four and two are announced, the test passes. If the number forty-two is announced, the test fails.

[OPTIONAL] speech-050 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak-as literal-punctuation

Tests support for speaking out digits in a number one at a time.

for (var i = 0; i += 1; i++) { print 'hello' . ' ' . 'world'; }

If the semicolons, periods, parentheses, braces and quotation marks are announced in the preceding line of code, the test passes.

[OPTIONAL] speech-060 CSS3 Speech: -epub-speak-as no-punctuation

Tests support for speaking out digits in a number one at a time.

I said: here be dragons; there be The Killer Rabbit of Caerbannog

If the colon is not announced and no pause occurs after the semicolon, the test passes.